翻译，时间轴，压制：旋火
Hello, it's Scott Manley here.
你好 这是Scott Manley
With a Kerbal Space Program video,
制作一期坎巴拉太空计划的视频
because well I haven't done one in a very long time
因为我很长一段时间没做这个游戏的视频了
注：这是指这期视频
Every Chinese Rocket Design Explained!
https://youtu.be/kDX5jRo27JY
and honestly I've been struggling talking about the history of the Chinese rocket program
而且实话说 我一直在努力做谈论中国的火箭计划历史的视频
that I decided to stop and do something light
我决定停下来 做一点轻量级的东西
well I decided that I would try to fly to the moon in Kerbal Space Program
好 我决定 我会尝试在KSP里登月
using nothing but solid rocket motors
只用固体火箭发动机
after all we've just had the Moar Boosters!!! update
毕竟我们刚刚得到了Moar Boosters!!!(KSP 1.8 191016)的更新
which added more boosters including the Thoroughbred and the Clydesdale boosters
这增加了更多的助推器包括Thoroughbred(纯种马)和Clydesdale(克莱德谷马)助推器
Now these are two point five meter boosters
这俩是2.5米助推器
and as well as providing lots of thrust and lots of propellant
能同时提供大量的推力和大量的推进剂
they also do something that they previously didn't do in Kerbal Space Program
他们也做了些之前KSP没出现过的东西
they have thrust vectoring
就是固体火箭有了矢量推力
Because a lot of people don't realize that real solid rocket Motors can have thrust vectoring.
因为很多人没有意识到 现实中的固体火箭发动机可以有推力矢量
They are technological items
它们是科学的东西
Sure they have a combustion chamber.
所以会有燃烧室
They have a nozzle and that nozzle can be vectored.
矢量喷嘴
Anyway I taken a very unorthodox launch profile here.
不论如何 我在这里采取了非常特殊的发射配置
You notice that I went straight up the reason is I calibrated
你会发现我是直着发上去的 原因是
each of these first two stages to get me exactly into a nice circular orbit.
我通过前两级火箭进行校准来让我到达一个漂亮的圆形轨道
So I go straight up and then when I can I get straight up
所以 我垂直上升 然后当我完成了直线上升的阶段
I turn the thing across and point it at 90°.
然后我把这个东西垂直翻转到90度方向
Well, okay wait for thrust vectoring to kick in.
好吧 等待推力矢量起作用
注：参考dv地图
forum.kerbalspaceprogram.com
/index.php?/topic/87463-173-community-delta-v-map-27/
And, yep more or less this thing has exactly the amount of delta-v that I should need to get into a circular orbit
而且 这个火箭有着恰好能让我进入圆轨道的dv
So one thing you'll notice here that is
你会发现
that I will try to get my time to at apogee to hang around zero.
我会尽量让我距离远地点的时间为0(左下角)
I'm essentially trying to control my my sink rate or my vertical speed.
根本上是我想控制爬升率或者说垂直速度
So that it remains very close to zero.
使它非常接近于零
Are there you go look beautiful 87 and just over a hundred kilometers.
结束加速时近地点87km远地点仅超过100km多一点 很完美
That's not bad for having 2 Rocket Motors that I have zero control over.
对于包含两个无法控制的固体火箭而言 这个水平很不错了
Or rather all the control comes from deciding the delta-v of each stage.
或者说所有的控制来自决定每一个阶段的dv
So this next stage for the trans-lunar injection
因此 对于月球转移轨道的下一级
is 866m/s so to do this I'm just going to put 866m/s into my maneuver node
需要866m/s 所以要做到这一点 我只需要把866m/s加到我的动作节点
I know I'm just going to adjust the time that maneuver happens.
现在只需要调整到机动点发生的时候
So that puts me as close to the Moon as possible.
使得轨道越接近月球越好(来节省dv)
This is the new maneuver planner that was added a few versions ago
这是被几个版本前添加了新的机动规划器
And it is very very helpful I'm going to say.
我认为这很有用
I mean there are significant challenges of navigating a spacecraft using solid rocket Motors in real life.
我的意思是在现实生活中使用固体火箭发动机航行的航天器比较难以操纵
In particular you know that you can actually get the level of precision
特别是你可以得到的精度水平
that I'm getting in Kerbal Space Program because we don't know the exact delta-v.
未必有KSP这种程度 因为我们不知道确切的dv
Typically you are got a margin of error of a few percent.
通常你有百分之几的误差
And in this particular case a difference of a few percent could send you off into deep space.
而在这种特殊情况下的百分之几的差异可能会把你发送到深空
And you would miss things completely.
而你会完全错过一些事物
In the case of New Horizons, it's solid rocket final stage actually over performs
在新视野号的案例中  它的固体火箭性能过度了(3级火箭ATK Star 48B)
and they had to spend some time using the liquid propellant engines to slow the spacecraft down
他们不得不花了些时间用液体推进剂发动机来让航天器减速
so it would actually make its Jupiter encounter with the right time.
使它能恰好和木星相遇
So next challenge is getting into orbit around the Moon.
那么下一个挑战是进入绕月球轨道运行
Now you can just fire your engines and sequence
现在 你可以发动你的引擎和分级序列
but I really want to get the perigee as close to the surface of the Moon as possible.
但我真的想要近地点尽可能地靠近月球的表面
So I came up with this two-stage maneuver
所以 我想出了这个两级机动
where I am make one maneuver that actually puts me closer
在那里我做一个机动 实际上使我更接近
and then the second one which breaks me into a sort of elliptical orbit
然后经过第二个机动之后变成某种椭圆轨道
that passes close to the surface.
这种轨道很接近表面
It turns out 3 stage correction burns I can use but I've only I'm only going to need two of them.
我可以使用其中的三级 但我只需要其中的两个
It was a spare one there if I needed it.
这是一个备份
I over respect the whole thing but I didn't want to take it out obviously
我给整个过程留有余量 但显然我当时不想用它
because the delta-v of every previous stage depends upon the mass of the upper stage
因为前一级的dv取决于上面级(后一级)的质量
is one of these things where you realize you know
换句话说
if you cut things down you then have to rebalance every stage.
如果你减少了一级的质量 你需要重新调整每一级的dv
So now, I mean in 8 kilometers above the surface
所以 现在在8公里的高度
and I want to slow the heck down
我想减速
And I'm going 579m/s out.
要减掉579m/s
I could orbit around one more time.
我可以多绕一圈
But I decided I'm just going to go straight for the landing gear.
但我决定 直接开始整个减速过程 直到打开起落架着陆
So I actually what I do is I just dumped these extra stages.
于是现在把所有多余的分级扔掉
I know I'm going to go for the landing.
因为要准备着陆了
So for the landing I have more delta-v for this first burn
对于着陆而言 第一次点火的这一级火箭
than I have in orbital velocity.
相比轨道速度有着更多的dv
So if I just burn that it would mean that I would start going backwards.
所以 如果我等它烧完 我会开始逆行
What I instead do is point downwards the 30 degree angle.
所以我不这样做 而是指向向下30度
And because of cosine losses, my delta-v decreases faster than my Surface velocity.
而由于余弦损失 我的dv会比相对地表速度减小的幅度大
And so at some point the surface velocity and the delta-v display on the left get very close.
到了某一刻 两者会非常接近
And then I Yeah tell it to point retrograde and now I'm actually slowing down.
到了这时 开始指向逆行方向 现在开始真正地减速
Safe in the knowledge that I will reach pretty much 0 velocity over the surface at some reasonable altitude.
肯定地说 我会在某个高于月表的高度达到几乎0速度
Now if I had too much delta-v I could end up just puddling straight into the surface.
现在如果剩下了太多dv没有无法减掉 就会撞上
I should also point out that this engine I set it up to use only 30% thrust
我还要指出的是 这台发动机我将它设置为只使用30％的推力
because I want to be able to think my way through this situation.
因为我希望在这种情况下有思考解决方法的时间
Do the math in my head.
顺便计算
So I'm close enough to the surface now that you can actually see rocks.
现在已经足够接近表面 甚至能看到岩石了
It's there's several rocket's gear that I could use for the landing.
它有几个火箭起落架 可以用来降落
I'm just going to use these
我这次就要使用这些
These are the new ones.
更新里添加的
These are the Mite motors by the way.
这些都是Mite(虫)火箭发动机
They're 0.65 meter engines.
它们是0.65米直径的引擎
And they are rather nice.
还行
So they are strong at the outside for the simple reason.
强壮的它们被放在外部 原因很简单
When I hit the stage command it will separate the decouplers
当我按下分级命令(指空格按键) 将会打开分离器
and they will pop off so I wait until my velocity gets down to zero.
然后脱离 所以现在等速度到0的时候
And then I will detach them
然后我将它们分开
and then I will have controlled my descent.
然后我就已经控制了我的下降过程
You see.
你瞧
So you're mounting them in pairs on the outside and dropping them means I can control.
所以 在外部成对安装它们并成对分离它们 意味着这个过程我可以控制
I'm finally a trick from the Soviet lunar landing program
我终于从苏联登月计划中学到一招
using the Rocket Motors as the separator tries to push myself on to the ground
使用火箭发动机作为分离器并试图把自己按在地上
and make sure I don't bounce around too much.
来防止着陆器弹跳得太厉害
And look at that I got on.
这样我就着陆了
I actually had several stages worth of landing Rockets still to use
其实我有着陆用火箭尚未使用
that I can do to iterate on.
通过它们我可以反复尝试着陆过程
But got to the surface.
但毕竟现在着陆了
Planted the flag for your posterity.
为你的后代插旗
注：肯尼迪登月演讲梗
We choose to go to the Moon not because it's easy.
我们选择去月球 不是因为它很容易
But because there's great potential for explosions.
而是因为有很大的可能发生爆炸
I got all these extra stages
我有这些额外的分级
so I'm going to try and get home more or less without changing direction
所以我要尝试回家 但不需要改变飞行方向
Just so happens I landed pretty much on the side of the moon which is retrograde
因为我恰巧降落在月球上 相对月球绕地公转逆行的那一侧
so I can just keep the same orientation
这样我就可以保持(和减少月球轨道公转速度)相同的方向
the spacecraft will eventually get me home.
飞船最终会让我回家
I mean clearly I could have built a much smaller vehicle and go all the way home.
很显然 我可以造一个更小的载具并成功返回
These small engines aren't actually that if efficient.
这些小型发动机的效率其实不是很高
But I kind of wanted to have lots of options at every stage
但是我想在每个阶段都保持一定的冗余能力
to make sure that if something went wrong,
确保一旦发生任何问题
contingencies to make sure that
或者意外
if I needed to make course corrections, there were ways to do it.
需要的话 就能修正方向
Having lots of small rockets makes the thing a lot more controllable.
有许多小火箭 使事情更可控
Indeed in one of the earliest written down plans for a rocket to the moon
事实上 在最早的已成的纸面计划之一里
actually used clusters of black powder rocket.
有实际使用黑火药火箭群的方案
And they would have these big hexagonal bases
这个方案里有多个大六边形基座
and they would fire them by pulling the strings I think.
说不定是用绳索点燃
It's kinda ridiculous but of course they would do their the navigation by hand.
这听起来有点可笑 但他们会使用手动导航
And once they figured out, they would point the rocket in the correct direction
如果他们计算无误 他们会将火箭指向正确的方向
and fire as many motors as they need.
然后点燃尽可能多的发动机
It explains like that
它的这种解释
that make me realize that real life can be way more Kerbal than Kerbal Space Program.
使我意识到 现实生活中有很多比KSP还KSP的东西
All I'm doing here. This maneuver is bringing my descent rate was going to be too fast.
我在这里做这个动作 是因为我的下降率会太快
I was going to plunge to deep through the atmosphere to quickly.
我会过快地通过大气层
So I'm firing the engine.
所以我点燃发动机
It's 90° to lift my orbit up.
是径向向外的方向来抬升我的轨道
So I will now fall through the atmosphere in glide to make a safe descent.
因此 我将通过在大气层 滑翔下降并安全降落
Now I can get back to actually writing about Chinese rockets and other things.
现在我可以回去 实实在在地去写有关中国火箭和其他东西的稿子了
I just felt that I needed to post a Kerbal Space Program video to break the writer's block.
我只是觉得 我需要发布一个KSP的视频来解除脑闭塞的状态
Maybe that's what it is. I don't know.
也许是这样吧
I look forward to coming up with some more science or history or rockets or...
我期待着未来与一些科学或历史或火箭或...
God there's so many things I want to talk about.
我想谈很多事情
Sometimes the hard part is just figuring out what.
有时候 最困难的部分就是不知道该做啥
And also making sure that I do it at a level of quality that makes me happy
而且要保证达到一个让我满意的水平
because I don't like to cut corners.
因为我不喜欢偷工减料
I do like to play Kerbal Space Program.
我确实喜欢KSP
I guess I like to procrastinate a lot.
我觉得我重度拖延
Sometimes that's the big problem.
有时候 这是个很大的问题
I mean maybe I should do a video on solid rocket motors.
我的意思是 也许我应该做固体火箭发动机的视频
But boy, that is an interesting subject
这可是一个有趣的话题
Did you know that the first solid rocket motor that is matched the modern design of green and binder?
你知道吗 第一个现代的环保粘合的固体火箭发动机(是谁设计的吗)
Was Jack Parsons.
是Jack Parsons
Jack Parsons you put basically asphalt in a regular mixture well explosives and stabilizer in.
Jack Parsons提出了把沥青和炸药还有稳定剂混合在一起
Bang. He had a solid rocket motor while I mean it didn't go bang it burned.
砰的一下他得到了一个固体火箭发动机 当然它点火的时候不是真的砰的一下
Yeah. Jack Parsons, the same guy found the JPL.
就是那个创建了喷气推进实验室的Jack Parsons
And found Aerojet Rocketdyne and also had Aleister Crowley as a spiritual advisor.
他也创建了Aerojet Rocketdyne公司 也信仰Aleister Crowley的那一套理论
So it was an interesting character if I do say so myself.
对我而言这是个有趣的人
So what's the conclusion of this successful challenge mission.
那么 对于这个成功的挑战任务的总结
Thanks everyone for tuning in and staying putting watching this.
感谢大家收看这期视频
I always appreciate your company.
我一直感谢你们的陪伴
I will be back with more science next time.
下次视频会带来更多的科学
I'm Scott Manley. Fly safe.
我是Scott Manley 祝你安全飞行